#### Contact

s-mahmoud\_gamal@zewailcity. edu.eg

www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-aboelfotoh-637312131 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Deep Learning
Natural Language Processing (NLP)

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
German (Elementary)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Conda Essentials

Image Processing with Keras in Python

Feature Engineering for NLP in Python

Linear Classifiers in Python
Introduction to Deep Learning in
Python

# mahmoud aboelfotoh

Machine Learning Engineer at Omdena Egypt

## Summary

I am a machine learning engineer who have passion towards filling the gap between industry and research. I was oscillating for the past two years between research internships/courses and real-life projects, then i realized that they are package deal and should not be separated.

Skills: Python, Machine learning, NLP, Deep learning, PyTorch.

## Experience

Omdena Machine Learning Engineer May 2021 - Present (8 months)

Upwork
Deep Learning Engineer
2019 - Present (2 years)

Zewail City of Science and Technology Junior Research Assistant (internship) June 2020 - August 2020 (3 months)

Our missions in this internship were to develop enhanced person identification and re-identification mechanisms, development of accurate real-time event and activity recognition models and provide an extended and consolidated understanding of camera scenes by integrating feeds from multiple cameras. To demonstrate the applicability and effectiveness of proposed techniques, EGYEYE, a video analytics module will be implemented for the video surveillance system in Zewail city.

Chegg Inc.

Programming Tutor February 2019 - May 2019 (4 months)

My main role as a tutor in Chegg was to help students overcome difficulties that face them while solving OOP problems or while understanding and

implementing Data structures or algorithms in C++ and python. In addition, i also helped students with Matlab problems.

# Education

Zewail City of Science and Technology

B.Sc. Degree, Communications and Information Engineering · (2016 - 2021)

Udacity

Deep Learning · (2021)